# Xie Fen

fenx@uw.edu, 206.201.4312 4428 Eastern Ave N, Seattle, WA

http://joyoverseas.com/

#### SUMMARY

Over 4 years industry experience with wide ranging job roles and diverse cultural backgrounds. Passionate in design technology and currently pursuing a master's degree in Human Computer Interaction and Design at University of Washington. Seeking for UI/UX designer position starting from fall 2015.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Product Manager**

03/2013-11/2013

Opera Software ASA, Beijing, China

- Coordinated 15+ people team and managed the new release of Opera Mini Chinese version for millions of monthly active users.
- Led 10 people team and launched Sphinx, a browser-based game engine in 3 months.

#### **QA Engineer**

06/2011-03/2013

Opera Software ASA, Beijing, China

- Developed 5+ Opera speed dial extensions, one of which reached 200,000 downloads.
- Led the outsourcing project of developing 10+ apps for Opera TV Store.
- Presented Opera products in exhibitions and gave speeches in developer conferences.
- Conducted quality assurance work on Opera Desktop, Mobile and TV Store, including automated testing.

#### **Software Engineer**

08/2007-08/2008

Infosys Technologies Limited, Shanghai, China

- Developed banking backend services under Mainframe system using Cobol and DB2.
- Collected and analysed customer requirements onsite.

# **SKILLS**

## **Design Methods**

Wireframe Prototyping Usability Testing

### **Design Tools**

Illustrator Photoshop InDesign After Effect Sketch

## **Programming**

HTML/CSS/Javascript
Python
Java
Cobol, DB2
Data Analysis (R, Rstudio)
Machine Learning (Octave)
Data Visualization

# **INTERNSHIP**

#### Sales Assistant

03/2010-09/2010

Ilmed Ventilazione Industriale, Torino, Italy

- Developed and maintained customer relationship, provided after sales support.
- Coordinated order processing between China and Italy offices, shortened delivery by improving process.

#### Software Intern

09/2006-04/2007

Infosys Technologies Limited, Mysore, India

- Got A in all the courses of 3 months' high-demanding Mainframe training.
- Led an 8 people team to achieve an evaluation of ranking A in the final project.

# **EDUCATION**

**Master of Human Computer Interaction & Design** 09/2014-08/2015 University of Washington, U.S.

**Master of Computer Engineering**, GPA 102/110 09/2008-12/2010 Politecnico di Torino, Italy

**B.S in Software Engineering**, GPA 87.8/100 09/2003-07/2007 Huazhong University of Science and Technology, China